Joseph Nganga Nungari



nungari100@gmail.com



+254798734442



linkedin.com/in/nungari100



https://nungari100.netlify.app/

Summary

I love creating software and building systems that help users interact with and share their experiences. From the time I was in college, I've been interested in programming and systematically figuring out ways to build more efficient and usable systems. I have been coding on my own for the past 3 years mostly in python, while I was working in a cyber shop, and enjoyed it so much that I decided to join Moringa School where I spent 1200 hours over 6 months writing code and building real applications. In addition to what I had learned frameworks such as Angular, flask, and Django were introduced in my time there. All of the activities at Moringa are practical, and project and team-based, so at the end of Moringa School, I worked both as an engineer and Scrum Master on a team of 4 people to build a full -scale application for recipe lovers to easily find local recipes online and shop for the recipes.

I also enjoy meeting new people and hearing new perspectives .Reach out of you want to talk to me about emerging new tech, creating software products or football.

Experience

CEO

Madrocks Networkers

Dec 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months +)

- .Leading the development of the company's short- and long-term strategy
- .Creating and implementing the company vision and mission
- .Evaluating the work of other executive leaders within the company, including directors, vice presidents, and presidents
- .Maintaining awareness of the competitive market landscape, expansion opportunities, industry developments, etc.
- .Ensuring that the company maintains high social responsibility wherever it does business
- .Assessing risks to the company and ensuring they are monitored and minimized
- .Setting strategic goals and making sure they are measurable and describable

online work

Upwork

May 2017 - Present (4 years 1 month +)

- .Provide quality customer service
- .Processes customer and account source documents by reviewing data for deficiencies.
- . Verifying accuracy and sorting information to prepare source data for computer entry(data entry operator)
- .Reviewing data for deficiencies or errors, correcting any incompatibilities and checking output(data entry operator)
- .Expand shorthand notes(Transcriptionist)
- .Transcribe live meetings
- .Keep transcriptions organized for later use

Sales Manager

E-tric

Jan 2019 - Present (2 years 5 months +)

- .Handle cash and card transactions
- .Managing sales by developing a business plan that covers sales, revenue, and expense controls
- .Meeting planned sales goals
- .Understand our ideal customers and how they relate to products
- .Interpreting the facts about the character, quantity, and trend of demand through marketing research
- . Sell mechanical products that call for after-sale services such as installation repairs and maintenance

Education



Modcom Institute

certificate, Data Science- Machine Learning & Python Training

2020 - 2021

- .Pandas, built on top of numpy, adds data frames that offer critical data analysis functionality and features.
- . Visualizations to present results
- .Basics of machine learning and how to use sci-kit learn a powerful library for machine learning
- . Using the Natural Language Processing Toolkit (NLTK) library
- .Working with data from databases

Moringa School

Full-stack developer

2020 - 2020

- .HTML, CSS, and Git
- .JavaScript Fundamentals
- .JavaScript for Web and Front-End Development
- .Object-Oriented Programming and Git Collaboration

Licenses & Certifications



IT Essentials - Cisco

ID: 46456045

Software Engineer, Full stack - Moringa School

Skills

```
Cybersecurity • Sales • Full-Stack Development • Microsoft Office • Microsoft Word • Microsoft PowerPoint • Leadership • Public Speaking • Networking • Django
```

Honors & Awards



Cisco Networking Academy® Introduction to IoT course,

Mar 2017

Able to proficiently:

1.Install components to build, repair, or upgrade personal

computers.

- 2. Install and share a printer to meet requirements.
- 3.Implement basic host, data, and network security.
- 4. Troubleshoot advanced hardware and software problems.

Cisco Networking Academy ® Introduction to Cybersecurity course

Mar 2017

As per that time i was able to:

- Global implications of cyber threats
- Ways in which networks are vulnerable to attack
- · Impact of cyber-attacks on industries
- · Cisco's approach to threat detection and defense
- · Why cybersecurity is a growing profession
- Opportunities available for pursuing network security certifications intermediate skills in metasploit and other Ethical hacking tools